<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Flynn R Hill</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Flynn R Hill</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Multilevel logistic regression (again)</title>
      <link>/post/multilevel-logistic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/multilevel-logistic-regression/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended a whole-day workshop on multilevel modelling organised by NIASRA and taught by Professor Mark Tranmer, who is an expert in the field from the University of Glasgow.
Multilevel logistic regressionOne part of the workshop that I realised I didn’t have any familiarity with was the idea of how variance works in logistic regression, and in particular in a multilevel logistic regression.
Here is one way of looking at logistic regression, in a formulation that reflects how a glm works:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Logistic Regression</title>
      <link>/post/hierarchical-logistic-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hierarchical-logistic-regression/</guid>
      <description>This one is just a snippet. I was reading through the Stan manual (version 2.17.0), and it has some nice examples of Stan models in chapter III, however, only the Stan model code is given for these. I decided to make a data simulation to try one out, specifically, the model in section 9.9: Hierarchical Logistic Regression.
The Stan code from the manual looks like this (after substituting the suggested improvements on pages 140-141).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying an educational effect</title>
      <link>/post/outcomespost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/outcomespost/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I will run through a simple simulation using only base R, and demonstrate a way to do power analysis by using this simulation. Say we have a cohort of 500 first-year students commencing their second session of study. We decide to offer a special tutoring service to some of the students who did not go well in their first session. To do this, we arrange students in ascending order of their averaged first session final marks, and go down the list calling students and offering tutoring services until 50 students have taken up the offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation and Modelling in R and Stan</title>
      <link>/post/post_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post_1/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I simulate an example experiment in which there is a non-linear relationship with underlying parameters that vary by group membership, before fitting the data using Bayesian regression in Stan. In this example, inspired by a real-world problem (with details changed to protect future Nobel prize winners, so try not to read too much into it), several mutant strains of a species of bacteria have been exposed to a range of concentrations of Chemical X.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>