<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Flynn R Hill</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Flynn R Hill</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying an educational effect</title>
      <link>/post/outcomespost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/outcomespost/</guid>
      <description>Say we have a cohort of 500 first-year students commencing their second session of study. We decide to offer a special tutoring service to some of the students who did not go well in their first session. To do this, we arrange students in ascending order of their averaged first session final marks, and go down the list calling students and offering tutoring services until 50 students have taken up the offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation and Modelling in R and Stan</title>
      <link>/post/post_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/post_1/</guid>
      <description>In this example, inspired by a real-world problem (with details changed to protect future Nobel prize winners, so try not to read too much into it), several mutant strains of a species of bacteria have been exposed to a range of concentrations of Chemical X. Individual bacteria are exposed, and their response is to either turn green (success) or not. Intriguingly, if a lot of trials are measured of a range of concentrations for a single strain (mutant A, below), there is a bell curve-shaped rise and fall in successes as a function of concentration.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>